brighthorizons.com 2015-12-07

# Website Privacy Policy | Bright Horizons® | Bright Horizons®

**Welcome**

Bright Horizons is committed to protecting the confidentiality, integrity and security of your personal information and we take this responsibility very seriously. This privacy policy covers Bright Horizons' practices for collecting and processing information about its customers, prospective customers, employees, subcontractors/suppliers, students/apprentices, website visitors and job applicants. 

**Who controls personal information collected by Bright Horizons?**

In the United States, Canada, and India Bright Horizons Family Solutions LLC (through its related affiliates) is the data controller for the information collected about you. Our world headquarters are located at 200 Talcott Avenue South, Watertown, Massachusetts 02472, USA.

In the United Kingdom, Bright Horizons Family Solutions Limited (Co. No. 2328679) is the data controller for the information collected about you. Its registered office is located at 2 Crown Court, Rushden, Northamptonshire, NN10 6BS, UK. 

In Ireland, Bright Horizons Family Solutions Ireland Limited (Co. No. 288883) is the data controller for the personal information collected about you. Its registered office is located at College Business & Technology Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland. 

In the Netherlands, Kindergarden Nederland B.V.(Co. No. 33303797) is the data controller for the personal information collected about you. Its registered office is located at Herengracht 244, 1016 BT Amsterdam, Netherlands. 

**Is Bright Horizons Safe Harbor Certified?**

Bright Horizons Family Solutions LLC obtained Safe Harbor certification for personal information it receives from the European Economic Area. Bright Horizons has committed to handling such personal information in accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles (the "Principles"). We use a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with the Principles and periodically verify that this policy is accurate and comprehensive, implemented properly, and accessible. We have agreed to work with relevant Data Protection Authorities, if individuals raise compliance concerns with them. 

Our certification can be found at: <https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx> 

For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Website at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>

**Why does Bright Horizons collect personal information?**

We limit the collection of information to what is necessary to provide you with high quality services, to support your specific needs and requests, and to meet our business needs in connection with the services. Below we have highlighted the reasons for the collection of your personal information: 

  * To respond adequately to your requests for services or information; 
  * To provide services to individuals, families and employers that includes child care and other dependent care, education (general, higher and accredited education), wellbeing, work/life, and consulting; 
  * To provide a safe, healthy, and successful environment for those to whom we provide services; 
  * To provide resource material/information regarding our services and areas of interest to our customers, such as parenting, child care, adult care, education, wellbeing, and work/life balance, among other things; 
  * To aid in the administration of our services to our customers; 
  * To administer first aid, emergency and other medical care, when necessary;
  * To comply with laws, and government regulations/standards; 
  * To support our business purposes and functions related to the services, such as education, training, curriculum, communication, administration, and record-keeping; 
  * To provide utilization reports and other information to employers offering our services to its workforce; 
  * To facilitate and process payments for the services; 
  * To fulfil tax, reporting, and other financial requirements and obligations; 
  * To administer employee payroll, benefits, tax/regulatory compliance and other record keeping and administration requirements; and 
  * To consider applications for employment and accredited education. 

**How do you consent to Bright Horizons' use of your personal information?**

By providing your personal information, you are consenting to its collection, use and disclosure by Bright Horizons for the purpose outlined in this privacy policy. In light of the nature of our services, as well as applicable laws and regulatory requirements, if you choose to withhold some types of personal information or opt out of providing it, we may not be able to provide the services requested. 

**What personally identifiable information does Bright Horizons collect?**

The type of business relationship you have with Bright Horizons will determine the specific information we will need to collect from you. 

  * Information necessary to perform the service that you provide voluntarily when registering (whether by telephone, online or in person) or during the course of services. Depending on the type of service engaged, the information requested may include your personalized registration user name and password; payment and contact details; a dependent's name, date of birth, gender, allergies, food restrictions, special needs, health information, and emergency contact details for doctors and alternative carers; or school transcripts, applications, registration and enrolment information. 
  * Utilization information, such as dates of service, type of service, user of service and reasons for service. 
  * Records created during the course of providing service to you or your dependents such as caretaker notes on the activities, behaviours, illnesses, medication, food, etc.; photographs; and other documentation records. 

If you are prospective customer, we will collect: 

  * Contact information that you provide voluntarily when requesting publications or other information via telephone, online or in person. Contact information may include your name, telephone/fax number, and email/mailing address. 

If you are an employee, apprentice/student or applicant, we will collect: 

* Typical information that you provide voluntarily via telephone, online or in person including your name, mailing/email addresses, telephone/fax number, employment history with job descriptions, education, references, affiliations and other relevant information for payroll, benefits and administration.

****  
** Where does Bright Horizons store personally identifiable information? **

  * Electronic Information: Although some information may remain on electronic storage data systems in the country where originally provided, the electronic personal information we collect will also be stored and processed on electronic information systems in the United States. As a result, United States governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through applicable laws. Bright Horizons transfers personal information to the United States in compliance with all laws of the originating country, including the European Union's Data Protection Directive.
  * Hardcopy Information: The hardcopy of personal information we collect will remain in the country where you receive the services or provided the information ** **

****Who does Bright Horizons share personally identifiable information with?** **

Bright Horizons considers your personal information confidential and does not share it with others except as described in this privacy policy. There are limited circumstances that require Bright Horizons to disclose your personal information to others in order to deliver services or to meet Bright Horizons' necessary business purposes. We may disclose your information, as necessary to the following: 

  * **To your Employer** : Bright Horizons services are often made available to you as a benefit through employer-sponsored programs. In order to meet our obligations to your employer, Bright Horizons will provide details of your use of the services to your employer, which may include your name, dates of use, reasons for use, and other available details. We will disclose only information relevant to the utilization of the services. 
  * **To Subcontractors and Other Agents** : We sometimes employ or contract with other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, such as providing dependent care services, recruiting services, and supporting our systems and call centers. Depending upon the type of service they are providing, we may share sensitive data only as appropriate and necessary for the performance of the service. These parties are under contractual obligations to use your personal information only as needed to perform these functions and agree to handle such data in accordance with Bright Horizons information security and confidentiality standards, and this privacy policy. 
  * **For Business Transfers** : As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy assets. If any Bright Horizons business unit is sold or substantially all of Bright Horizons is acquired, personal information relevant to the operation sold could be transferred as part of the transaction. 
  * **To Meet Legal Requirements** : We may share personally identifiable information with law enforcement or other government entities as required by law/regulations or as we reasonably determine to be necessary to protect our rights or the rights of others, to prevent harm to persons or property, to fight fraud, or to enforce our web site terms of use. 

**How can individuals access or update their personally identifiable information?**

Bright Horizons is committed to collecting personal information that is accurate, complete, current and reliable for its intended use. If you would like to access or update your personal information, or obtain copies of the information, the following steps can be taken by you: 

For informal requests: 

> 1\. If you have established an online user account with Bright Horizons, you may log onto your account to access and update your information. 
> 
> 2\. If you receive services from us, you may contact the program or location that stores or processes your information (such as a nursery/center where your child is enrolled). Bright Horizons may require you to make your request in writing to verify your identity. 
> 
> 3\. Alternatively, you may contact us as provided below. 

For subject access request under a Data Protection Act in the United Kingdom, Ireland or Netherlands: 

> 1\. You will need to complete the Bright Horizons' Data Subject Request Form [below] and send it (and the required payment) to the attention of the Legal Department, Bright Horizons, 2 Crown Court, Rushden, Northamptonshire, NN10 6BS United Kingdom. 

**How can individuals contact Bright Horizons?**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this privacy policy or how we are handling your personal information, please contact us as follows: 

United States, Canada and India 

  * Mail: Attn - Legal Department, 200 Talcott Avenue South, Watertown, MA 02472 USA
  * Email: dataprivacy@brighthorizons.com

United Kingdom, Ireland and Netherlands 

  * Mail: Attn - Legal Department, 2 Crown Court, Rushden, Northamptonshire, NN10 6BS UK
  * Email: dataprivacy@brighthorizons.com 

If your concern relates to how we process your data under our Safe Harbor certification and it cannot be resolved through our internal process listed above, we have agreed to dispute resolution using the relevant Data Protection Authorities as a third party resolution provider. 

**Will this Privacy Policy change?**

This privacy policy is subject to change and we will post revisions on our website. Please check back periodically, especially before you provide any personal information. This privacy policy was last updated in January 2013. 

**How does Bright Horizons protect your personal information?**

Bright Horizons utilizes appropriate technical, administrative and physical safeguards to protect against loss, unauthorized access, destruction, misuse, modification and improper disclosure of the personal information we collect in both physical and electronic format. We provide information security awareness training to our staff and conduct periodic quality assurance audits. However, no computer system or information can ever be fully protected against every possible hazard. As a result, Bright Horizons cannot guarantee the security and privacy of the information you provide to us. 

In addition, you play a valuable part in protecting the security of your information. Your password to access your registration information should never be shared with anyone and should be changed frequently. After you have finished using our site, you should log out and exit your browser to prevent unauthorized users from returning to your online Bright Horizons account. If you believe that someone has improperly used or provided information about you that you did not authorize, please contact us immediately in one of ways provided below. 

**What are the terms for you to use Bright Horizons websites?**

Bright Horizons websites are intended for use by adults. Bright Horizons does not solicit or knowingly collect any information from visitors under 18 years of age. Please do not use any of our websites if you are not yet 18 years old or of the age of majority where you reside. Bright Horizons website may contain links or references to other websites. Please be aware that we do not control other websites and that this privacy policy does not apply to those websites. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit. Your use of any Bright Horizons website is subject to our Terms of Use. Terms of Use How does Bright Horizons collect information on its websites? There are two ways Bright Horizons may collect information: actively (when you voluntarily enter your personal information as described in this policy), or passively as described below. 

1\. Passive Information Collection: As you navigate through a website, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies and means, such as Internet Protocol addresses, cookies, Internet tags, and navigational data collection. 

2\. Internet Protocol (IP) Addresses: This site uses Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP Address is a number assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider so you can access the Internet and is generally considered to be non-personally identifiable information, because in most cases an IP address is dynamic (changing each time you connect to the Internet), rather than static (unique to a particular user's computer). We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our server, report aggregate information, determine the fastest route for your computer to use in connecting to our site, and administer and improve the site. 

3\. Cookies: Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Most web browsers allow some control of cookies through browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org. The bullets and chart below explains further the cookies we use and why. 

  * "Session" cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your Web browser window or otherwise turn your computer off. Session cookies are used to improve navigation on websites and to collect aggregate statistical information. This site uses session cookies. 
  * "Persistent" cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of purposes, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (e.g., passwords), helping to determine what areas of the Web site visitors find most valuable, and customizing the Web site based on your preferences. This site uses persistent cookies. 
  * "Internet tags" (also known as single-pixel GIFs, clear GIFs, invisible GIFs, and 1-by-1 GIFs) are smaller than cookies and tell the website server information such as the IP address and browser type related to the visitor's computer. This site uses Internet tags. Tags have been placed both on online advertisements that bring people to the site and on different pages of the site. These tags indicate how many times a page is opened and which information is consulted. We do not collect or seek personally identifiable information through these tags. 
  * "Navigational data" ("log files," "server logs," and "clickstream" data) are used for system management, to improve the content of the site, market research purposes, and to communicate information to visitors. This site uses navigational data. 
  * For information on the specific cookies used on our websites please visit the link below to view Cookies utilised for the relevant website you are visiting.
